Inventory of the Saul Landau papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Saul Landau papers
1969-2000
2001C54
Landau, Saul.
2 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 motion picture film reel (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Interview transcripts, correspondence, sound recording, videotape cassettes, and motion picture film reels, relating to political conditions and revolutionary movements in Latin America.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2001.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Saul Landau, an internationally-known American scholar, author, commentator, and filmmaker, has focused on foreign and domestic policy issues. Landau produced more than forty films on social, political and historical issues, and worldwide human rights.
Scope and Content of Collection
Interview transcripts, correspondence, sound recording, videotape cassettes, and motion picture film reels, relating to political conditions and revolutionary movements in Latin America.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Radicalism--Latin America.; Latin America--Politics and government.; Videotapes; Motion pictures; Phonotapes
Collection Contents
- Videotapes and films, 1969-2000. (Box 1)
  Mainly VHS tapes of Saul Landau's short films and documentaries on various Latin American regions' social, political, economic, and human rights issues.
  - Video tapes, 1969-2000 (Box 1)
    - Fidel, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Brazil, Report on the Torture, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Que Hacer, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Case Officer, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Land of my Birth, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Paul Jacobs and the Nuclear Gangs, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Quest for Power, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Steppin, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Target Nicaragua, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Uncompromising Revolution, 1988 (Box 1)
    - The Sixth Sun: A Mayan Uprising in Chiapas, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Maquila: A tale of two Mexicos, 2000 (Box 1)
    - Losing Just the Same, Undated (Box 1)
  - Films, undated (Box 2)
    - "Uncomprimising Revolution," 16mm film, 2 reels, undated (Box On shelf)
- Sound recordings, 1995 (Folder 2)
  - "Manley's On Camera in Churchyard and Manley's voiceovers recorded at Bono's," 2 sound reels, 1980 (Folder 2: 1)
  - Interview with Subcomandante Marcos, Chiapas, 1 compact sound cassette and translation transcript, 1995 (Folder 2: 2)
- Transcripts, 1974-1977. (Box 2)
  Consists of interview and film transcripts on Latin America and Cuba
  - Fidel Castro interview transcripts, 1974-1977, undated (Box 2)
  - NEC Productions, Inc., 1974 (Folder 2: 3)
  - Barbara Walters, 1977 (Folder 2: 4)
  - Dan Rather, undated (Folder 2: 5)
  - Interview transcripts, undated (Folder 2: 6)
  - Interview transcripts from sound tapes, undated (Folder 3: 1)
  - Interviews with Cubans, undated (Folder 3: 2)
  - Maria Auxiliadora edited interview transcript, undated (Folder 3: 3)
  - Unidentified interview transcripts, undated (Folder 3: 4-5)
  - Brazil - A Report on Torture edited transcript, undated (Folder 3: 6)
  - Argos Servicios Informativos subtitle transcripts, undated (Folder 3: 7)
  - Unidentified film transcript, undated (Folder 3: 8)
  - Unidentified reel frame list and transcript, undated (Folder 3: 9)
  - Correspondence with Michael Manly, 1976-1977 (Folder 3: 10)